ALES Records 5225
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ALES Records
1920-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Labor Education Service (ALES)
5225
125.5 cubic feet
125.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Pamphlets and other documents re Brookwood Labor College available in this substantial collection. Unpublished guide Available.
9419357
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, April 19, 2017
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5225 C: ALES Course Materials 5225 E: ALES Labor Education Records 5225 I: ALES International Labor Records 5225 L: ALES Labor Plays 5225 S: ALES Scrapbooks 5657: American Labor Education Service Additional Documents
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; American Association for Adult Education; American Association for Labor Legislation; American Association for the United Nations; American Association of University Women; American Civil Liberties Union; American Committee on Economic Policy; American Council on Race Relations; American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Teachers. Workers Education Local 189; American Interracial Seminar; American Jewish Committee; American Labor Education Service; American Scandinavian Foundation; Americans for Democratic Action; Associated Research Council. Conference Board; Barnard Summer School for Women Workers in Industry; Brookwood Labor College (Katonah, N.Y.); Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers in Industry; Bryn Mawr School; Canada Labour Contress; Columbia University; Columbia University. Committee on Worker Education; Consumers' Research, Inc.; Cooperative League of the U.S.A; Encampment for Citizenship; Episcopal Church; European Productivity Agency; Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America; Ford Foundation. Fund for Adult Education; Girl Scouts of the United States of America; Highlander School; Hudson Shore Labor School; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.); International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; International Federation of Workers' Education Associations; International Industrial Relations Association; International Labour Organisation; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (A.F. of L.); Joint Committee of Organized Farmers and Workers; Julius Rosenwald Fund; League for Independent Political Action; League for Industrial Democracy; National Alliance of Postal and Federal Employees (U.S.); National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; National Association of Foreign Student Advisers (U.S.); National Committee for Extension of Labor Education; National Consumers' League; National Council for Permanent Fair Employment Practice Commission; National Council of Women; National Farmers' Union (U.S.); National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs; National Health and Welfare Retirement Agency; National Religion and Labor Foundation (U.S.); National Social Welfare Assembly; National Textile Workers' Union (U.S.); National Urban League; New Jersey Minorities Project; New Jersey State Industrial Union Council; New York Conference for Unemployment Insurance Legislation; New York (State). Legislature.; New York (State). Temporary Commission Against Discrimination; Pacific Coast Summer School; Postal Employees Institute; Rosenwald Assembly; Ruskind College (University of Oxford); Russell Sage Foundation; Sarah Lawrence College; Southern School for Workers (Richmond, Va.); St. Louis Missouri Project on Minorities; St. Louis Worker Education Committee; Textile Workers Union of America; United Nations; United States. Department of Labor; United States. Department of State; United States. Federal Emergency Relief Administration; United States. National Youth Administration; United States. Women's Bureau; United States. Works Progress Administration; United Transport Service Employees of America; University of Wisconsin. School for Workers; Vineyard Shore Labor School; Women's Conference Group; Women's Trade Union League; Workers' Education Bureau of America; Workers' Educational Association of Canada; Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A; Adams, Frances. (Frances Smith). 1907-1964.; Algor, Marie.; Anderson, Mary, 1872-1964.; Ault, Laura; Bellanca, Dorothy; Biemiller, Andrew J. (Andrew John), 1906-1982; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971; Ogden, Jean, 1897-1974; Cartwright, Morse A. (Morse Adams), 1890-; Coit, Eleanor G.; Colston, Warne; Comstock, Ada; Cook, Alice H., 1903-1988; Coyle, Grace Longwell, 1892-; Cummings, Frances; Dombrowski, James A. (James Anderson), 1897-1983; Douglas, Paul H.; Eichelberger, Clark M. (Clark Mell), 1896-1980; Elder, Arthur H.; Friedman, Ernestine; Gildersleeve, Virginia Crocheron, 1877-1965; Green, William, 1872-1952; Guazzo, Caesar; Henson, Francis; Hewes, Amy, 1877- 1970; Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1874-1971; Kaiser, Clara; Leslie, Mabel; Lindeman, Eduard; Magee, Elizabeth; Palmer, Gladys L. (Gladys Louise); Pancoast, Elinor, 1893-; Pell, Orlie (Orlie Anna Haggerty), 1900-; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Shoemaker, Alice; Smith, Hilda (Hilda Worthington); Starr, Mark, 1894-1985; Taylor, Harold, 1947; Willen, Pearl, (Pearl Larner), 1904-; Williamson, Margaret, 1889-; Wolfson, Theresa, 1897-1972
9419357
- Incorporation (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Re the incorporation of the Affiliated Schools for Workers, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constitutions, 1926-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Votes for constitutional change (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Board of Directors, 1927-1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Board of Directors, 1927-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Educational secretary's reports, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Executive committee, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Nominating committee, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Executive committee, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brochure for Board of Directors, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Reorganization committee, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Reorganization committee, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Committee on membership association, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Joint Administrative Committee (JAC) of ASW, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Joint Administrative Committee (JAC) of ASW, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Nominating committee for the JAC, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Nominating committee for the JAC, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Nominating committee for the JAC, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- JAC, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- JAC, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- JAC, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- JAC, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- JAC, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- JAC, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Educational Council minutes, 1929-1934 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Educational Council minutes, 1929-1934 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Educational Department, personnel, job analyses (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Educational Department, documents about (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Educational Department, district conferences (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Educational Department, specific form letters (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Educational council, report to JAC (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Publications sub-committee (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Educational Council, Committee on research (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Bryn Mawr Summer School (BMSS), Instruction committee and committee on courses, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Educational Council, Follow-up research committee (Box 1, Folder 36)
- College conference on Workers' education and collegiate committee (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Educational Department - finance (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Joint finance committee, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Samples of finance appeals (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Bulletins of affiliated schools for workers, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Educational secretary's reports on field trips and conferences (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Committee chairmen (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Study of recruiting and discussion of entrance requirements, includes Lucile Kohn (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Student essays about BMSS, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Research projects-general correspondence (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Educational council-general correspondence (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes Alice Shoemaker
- Mailing lists (BMSS etc. ) (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Faculty and students of the Barnard Summer School (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Re household employees (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Mailing lists for Barnard and BMSS (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Mailing lists for Barnard and BMSS (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Psychological tests (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Psychological tests (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Job history study committee (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Questionnaire on community service record (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Vineyard Shore Worker School (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Questionnaires, follow-up research study (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Shop and School, Summer School (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Committee on new schools, includes Mary Anderson, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Scrapbooks (Southern Summer School), Shop and School (Bryn Mawr Summer College) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Committee on development of new schools (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Vineyard Shore School (Scrapbook and Short Play) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Council on new schools, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook (Southern Summer School for Workers) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Committee on the pooling of materials (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Classroom Documents - Barnard Summer School (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Economic reference file (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Classroom Documents - Barnard Summer School (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Lots of documents: Syllabi, notes, lectures.
- Recruiting committee, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Barnard Summer School - Classroom Documents. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  See folder 7 notes.
- Old orders for Educational Department library (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Documents - Bryn Mawr Summer College for Workers (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Local classes includes letter re: North Bennett Street School, Boston, Mass (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Barnard Summer School for Women Workers (Box 2, Folder 10)
  More documents.
- Local study projects, questionnaires, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- University of Wisconsin Summer School for Workers in Industry (Box 2, Folder 11)
  A lot of documents of the Summer School for Workers in Industry at the University of Wisconsin
- Bibliography, correspondence re: books for local classes (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Presentations from the Southern Summer School for Women Workers (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Student news, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  includes Baltimore Workers' Education committee, Toledo, Reading, Pa.
- Analysis of job history questionnaires Article by Helen Hunneman, "Women workers in prosperity and depression." (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Extracts from students' letters, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Questionnaires and reports on local study groups, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Lists of workers' education centers (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Forms for BMSS re: students' industrial experience (Box 2, Folder 18)
- forms relating to study materials (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Follow-up study correspondence (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Magazine material (student autobiographies, mss.), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Student autobiographies (ts. transcripts) and faculty discussions (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Second year students, interviews (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Student autobiographies (mss. and tss. ) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Student autobiographies (mss. and tss. ) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Annotated lists of publications for workers' classes, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Pamphlet list (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Re: government printing of publications (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence res publications (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Mailing lists (Box 2, Folder 30)
- General correspondence (Box 2, Folder 31)
- General correspondence re publicity (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Educational Department Bulletin, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Jan to May
- Jean Carter. This America, 5 ts. copies and correspondence, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Jean Carter. This America, 5 ts. copies and correspondence, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- William Haber, Unemployment, a Problem of Insecurity, correspondence, drafts, publicity, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- William Haber, Unemployment, a Problem of Insecurity, correspondence, drafts, publicity, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- William Haber, Unemployment, a Problem of Insecurity, correspondence, drafts, publicity, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- William Haber, Unemployment, a Problem of Insecurity, correspondence, drafts, publicity, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Index to economic syllabi, 1926-1932 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Correspondence re bibliography of labor drama (Box 2, Folder 41)
- NRA and labor pamphlets, includes Mary Anderson (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Olga Law Plunder, Monograph on Methods of Teaching English to Workers' Classes, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  correspondence, ts. drafts and mimeograph led copies
- Olga Law Plunder, Monograph on Methods of Teaching English to Workers' Classes, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Olga Law Plunder, Monograph on Methods of Teaching English to Workers' Classes, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Olga Law Plunder, Monograph on Methods of Teaching English to Workers' Classes, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Jean Carter, Mastering the Tools of the Trade, correspondence, and ms. and ts. drafts, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Jean Carter, Mastering the Tools of the Trade, correspondence, and ms. and ts. drafts, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Jean Carter, Mastering the Tools of the Trade, correspondence, and ms. and ts. drafts, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Jean Carter, Mastering the Tools of the Trade, correspondence, and ms. and ts. drafts, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Miriam Bonner, A Summary of the International Labor Movement, ts. drafts, mimeographed copies, and correspondence, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Women's Bureau pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 1)
- BMSS fliers and ASW catalogue, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Gladys L. Palmer, A Scrapbook of the American Labor Movement, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  ms., ts. drafts, and mimeographed copies, correspondence
- Gladys L. Palmer, A Scrapbook of the American Labor Movement, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Gladys L. Palmer, A Scrapbook of the American Labor Movement, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Gladys L. Palmer, A Scrapbook of the American Labor Movement, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Gladys L. Palmer, A Scrapbook of the American Labor Movement, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Gladys L. Palmer, A Scrapbook of the American Labor Movement, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Katherine H. Pollak, Is There a Shrinking Week and a Growing Wane?, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  ts. draft, copies of first and second editions, correspondence
- Katherine H. Pollak, Is There a Shrinking Week and a Growing Wane?, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Katherine H. Pollak, Is There a Shrinking Week and a Growing Wane?, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Suggestions for training courses by Jean Carter (Box 3, Folder 12)
  including correspondence and bibliography on methods of teaching in Workers' education
- Syllabus on English pronunciation by Josephine Colby for BMSS, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- David Saposs lectures on "History of the Needles Trades" (Box 3, Folder 14)
  July to August, NY
- David Saposs lectures on "History of the Needles Trades" (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Amy Hewes, Women Workers in the Third Year of the Depression, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  includes correspondence with Mary Anderson
- Colston E. Warne, The World Economic Depression: a study of possible ways out, AAUW pamphlet, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Paid publication orders, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Recommendation to the Board re: study pamphlets, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Report on cities and organizations using publications, 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence re: publications, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Tarablyn and Brown fundraising report on BMSS, including notes, history, and report, 1927-1939 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- BMSS, reading lists (Box 3, Folder 23)
- BMSS, lists of students (Box 3, Folder 24)
- BMSS, Board of Directors, recommendations, agendas, minutes, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- BMSS, fliers, and programs, 1924-1934 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- BMSS, articles and speech by Mary Van Kleeck, "Women workers and the NRA", 1934 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- BMSS, student unemployment stories, 1928-1932 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  ts. transcripts ca. and edited version by Jean Carter and Gladys L. Palmer, "The American Worker and the American Scene."
- BMSS, typical applications, includes biographical data, essay on trade experience, and correspondence, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- BMSS, committees studying teachers' union (Box 3, Folder 30)
- BMSS, "Schools for Women Workers in Industry", 1929-1936 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- BMSS, Statistics, 1921-1933 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- BMSS, Statistics, 1921-1933 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- BMSS, Statistics, 1921-1933 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- BMSS, Statistics, 1921-1933 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- BMSS, Statistics, 1921-1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- BMSS, Introduction and outlines (Box 4, Folder 6)
- BMSS, Introduction and outlines (Box 4, Folder 7)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Economic organization (Box 4, Folder 8)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Consumption (Box 4, Folder 9)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Natural resources (Box 4, Folder 10)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Distribution (Box 4, Folder 11)
- BMSS, Course outlines: History (Box 4, Folder 12)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Labor legislation (Box 4, Folder 13)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Risks and social insurance (Box 4, Folder 14)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Social reorganization (Box 4, Folder 15)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Economics unit (Box 4, Folder 16)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Money and banking (Box 4, Folder 17)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Production (Box 4, Folder 18)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Labor movement (Box 4, Folder 19)
- BMSS. Course outlines: Specific industries (Box 4, Folder 20)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Women in industry (Box 4, Folder 21)
- BMSS, Course outlines: Wages and standard of living (Box 4, Folder 22)
- - BMSS, course outlines: Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 23)
- BMSS, planning, faculty includes Harriet Anlers, and Jean Carter, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Reports on BMSS students, 1929-1931 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Reports on BMSS students, 1929-1931 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Reports on BMSS students, 1929-1931 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Follow-up correspondence with students (Box 4, Folder 28)
- BMSS, workshop reports, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- BMSS, student reports, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- BMSS, student autobiographies and essays (Box 4, Folder 31)
- BMSS, special studies of high school students (Box 4, Folder 32)
- BMSS, lists of students by unit, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- BMSS, special projects (Box 4, Folder 34)
- BMSS, planning letters, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- BMSS, Applications for faculty, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- BMSS, Moving pictures, exhibits, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- BMSS, Speakers and program committee, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- BMSS, Warne unit, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  notes and stenographic reports on classes
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- BMSS, Palmer unit on economic history, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- BMSS, outline on Riley unit, "Making of Economic Man", 1930 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- BMSS, Amy Hewes unit, "Women Workers and the NRA", 1934 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- BMSS, Schedules, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Student autobiographies, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Southern workers, student autobiographies, 1923-1931 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Southern workers, student autobiographies, 1923-1931 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Traveling library, list of books, and correspondence, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Traveling library, list of books, and correspondence, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Traveling library, list of books, and correspondence, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Traveling library, list of books, and correspondence, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Book lists for worker-classes (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  correspondence, budgets, library committee members, publicity, and recruiting
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1921-1934 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  budget, publicity, correspondence, and reports
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Workers Daytime Classes of Columbia University Extension, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Proposal to New York State for Workers' education, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Planning for sectional conference, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Re: proposed clearing house (Box 5, Folder 36)
- YWCA summer conference (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Cooperation with YWCft (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Publicity (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Education, Department, general organization (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Correspondence re: field work, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Requests for assistance from other organizations (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Requests for material (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Correspondence re: publications, 1930-1934 (Box 5, Folder 44)